(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-08-08T13:01:57.038002",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
寒々 寒々… 夜の帳凍る言葉
Cold, so cold... Night's curtain, freezing words,
受け流して流れ星を待っていた
letting them pass as I waited for a shooting star.
光には遠い心で それでも
With a heart far from the light, even so,
輝きへと手を伸ばしたい
I want to reach out toward the radiance.
それに負うは 暴れる夢が痛い
For that, the raging dream hurts.
今は今は名も無き花
Right now, right now, a nameless flower.
以前の蕾だと 此の世の嵐を耐えながら描くよ
As a former bud, I'll paint while enduring the storm.
情熱は絶やさぬままで
Keeping my passion unquenched.
泣きそうなときは 泣いてしまえ
When you feel like crying, go ahead and cry.
それが 未来開花 魁となれ
That is the future blooming, becoming the pioneer.
瞳の純度は上がる事になるから
Because the purity of your eyes will rise.
泣きそうなときは泣いてしまえ
When you feel like crying, go ahead and cry.
日はそんなこともあると笑って
Laughing that days like that happen too.
涙と混ざり、希望よ
Mixing with tears, oh hope.
そんな感じ? 華麗に咲き誇る 前哨戦
Something like that? A preliminary battle blooming brilliantly.
花、さながら虎視眈々 仁、しかし梅香々々
Flowers, like koshitantan; benevolence, yet plum blossoms fragrant.
業、焦らず 雲、狙わず
Karma, not rushing; clouds, not aiming.
ねぇ、羽ばたいた心は
Hey, did my fluttering heart
今でも迷わずずっと飛べてるかな？
still fly straight without hesitation?
ねぇ、本当はやってみたいこと
Hey, the things I really want to do,
まだまだ隠し続けているでしょう？
I'm still keeping them hidden, aren't I?
悲しませないように
So as not to make you sad,
心配させないように
so as not to worry you,
数えきれない嘘をついて君の前で笑っていた
I told countless lies and smiled before you.
大切なものちゃんと守るために
To properly protect what's precious,
それはきっと間違いじゃないさ
surely that isn't a mistake.
これでは、いいのかな…？
Is this really okay...?
正しさは感情の後だった
Righteousness followed my emotions.
想いのない生き様になんて興味はないよ
I have no interest in a life without feelings.
変わり果てたこの世界にそっと乾杯を
A quiet toast to this completely changed world.
もう大丈夫何度も乗り越えた気持ちなんだ今日まで
It's okay, up until today I've overcome so much.
「ねぇ、それってお仕事なの？」
"Hey, is that your job?"
命を削るほど輝く光
A light shining enough to wear away life.
「ねぇ、あなたの夢は叶ったの？」
"Hey, did your dream come true?"
そう単純な話じゃないんだ
It's not such a simple story.
目を合わせたいのに
Even though I want to meet your eyes,
分かり合いたいのに
even though I want to understand each other,
茶化すような冗談を言って鏡の前で泣いていた
I made jokes and cried in front of the mirror.
きっと、辛いんだよ
I'm sure it's painful,
辛いと思っていいんだよ
and it's okay to feel that way.
それもきっと間違いじゃないさ
Surely that isn't a mistake either.
誰かのために生きたいから
Because I want to live for someone,
まずは自分のためにちゃんと生きておくんだ
first I must properly live for myself.
疲れ果てたその心にそっと乾杯を
A quiet toast to that exhausted heart.
もう大丈夫少しだけ待っていてね
It's okay, just wait a little longer.
優しさは強さだ
Kindness is strength.
正しさは感情の後だった
Righteousness followed my emotions.
想いのない生き様になんて興味はないよ
I have no interest in a life without feelings.
変わり果てたこの世界にそっと乾杯を
A quiet toast to this completely changed world.
もう大丈夫何度も乗り越えた気持ちなんだ
It's okay, my feelings have overcome so much.
これからも
From now on as well...
誰かのために生きたいから
Because I want to live for someone,
まずは自分のためにちゃんと生きておくんだ
first I must properly live for myself.
疲れ果てたその心にそっと乾杯を
A quiet toast to that exhausted heart.
もう大丈夫
It's alright now.
少しだけ待っていてね
Just wait a little longer.
優しさは強さだ
Kindness is strength.
ねぇ尋ねてよ本当の言葉を生きている鼓動を
Hey, ask me for my true words, for the beating of life,
痛みながらただ消えるようにまだ息をしたい
while hurting, so I can still breathe as I fade away.
理由があるの
Is there a reason?
不可視 作詞・作曲：ユリイ・カノン
[Song: Fukashi / Lyrics & Music: YurryCanon]
幸せだけを選んでいたって席は見えない
Even if I chose only happiness, my seat is out of sight.
過ぎ去った今を仕方ないなんて消せればいいけど
It would be nice if I could erase the past as something that couldn't be helped,
嘘で塗り固められる夢じゃない
but this isn't a dream built on lies.
ねぇ尋ねてよ本当の言葉を生きている鼓動を
Hey, ask me for my true words, for the beating of life,
闇に迷うのは一つじゃない道があるから
because there isn't just one path of wandering in the darkness.
欠けて求めてまた傷が増えてすべて捨て去れば
Lacking, seeking, increasing scars, if I threw everything away,
痛みなどないでも立ち尽くすだけじゃ見られない
there would be no pain—yet just standing still won't let me see it.
確かがあるの
Is there a certainty?
嘘で塗り固められる夢じゃない
This isn't a dream built on lies.
ねぇ尋ねてよ本当の言葉を生きている鼓動を
Hey, ask me for my true words, for the beating of life,
闇に迷うのは一つじゃない道があるから
because there isn't just one path of wandering in the darkness.
欠けて求めてまた傷が増えてすべて捨て去れば
Lacking, seeking, increasing scars, if I threw everything away,
痛みなどないでも立ち尽くすだけじゃ見られない
there would be no pain—yet just standing still won't let me see it.
確かがあるの
Is there a certainty?
信じていた人がいつか訪れると思っていた
I used to believe someone I trusted would visit me one day.
誰も同じと一人よけして目を逸らした
Thinking everyone is the same, I pushed them away and averted my eyes.
無理に使えた言葉飲み込んでしまった
I swallowed the words I was forced to use,
本当のことも隠してな嘘だ声を殺した
hiding even the truth, whispering lies, killing my voice.
心を滅かして過ぎ去りの姿生きていると言えるだろうか
Destroying my heart, can I say I'm living as I pass by?
だから不意の羽に気づいてよ
Therefore, notice my sudden wings—
レバー失って教えられて耐えて枯れてしまうけど
though I lose the level, am taught, endure, and wither away,
壊わぬより傷が増えても前に進んだんじゃない
rather than breaking without scars, didn't I push forward even as scars increased?
レギュレーター ほんとの言葉を
Regulator, true words...
生きてゆくこと どうかどうか
Living them out, please, please
その目に映して
reflect them in those eyes.
また夢を見た また夢を見よ
I dreamed again, let me dream again.
私も怖いけど 君がいれば
I'm scared too, but if you're here...
というわけで皆さんこんばんわー！
So everyone, good evening!
はい、ホロライブ4期生の常闇トワです！イエーイ！
Yes, I'm Tokoyami Towa from Hololive 4th Gen! Yay!
ということで、本日は、えー生誕祭、あ、今日はね、トワちゃんの誕生日なんです、ハッピーバースデー！
So today, um, birthday, ah, today is Towa-chan's birthday, Happy Birthday!
えーとは、トゥー・トワということで、
Um, Towa, as in "Two Towa", so...
えーお誕生日と、アンド、そして、アンド、そして、何回言うんだよって
Um, birthday and, and, and, and, how many times are you gonna say that!
えーなんと新衣装のお披露目もあります！イエーイ！
Um, and what's more, there's a new costume reveal too! Yay!
えー100万人記念もね、使って、あの、新衣装を作っていただきました！イエーイ！
Um, using the 1 million subscribers milestone too, they made a new costume for me! Yay!
そしてね、今日のライブなんですけどミニライブになっておりまして、大体30分から40分ぐらいで終わるんじゃないかなと思ってるんですけども、その短い時間でも楽しんでいただければなと思います、お願いいまーす！
And today's live is a mini-live, and I think it'll finish in about 30 to 40 minutes, but I hope you can enjoy even that short time. Please look forward to it!
はい、で、今回は、えっと、スープさんというね、会社にね、手伝ってもらって、今日のライブを作ってます！スープさんありがとう！
Yes, and this time, a company called SOUP helped me make today's live! Thank you SOUP!
そしてね、これ収録なんですけれども、収録の日に、なんかスープさんから、「え、なんかトワヤミ祭に応募したんですけど、外れました」みたいなこと言われて
And this is a recording, but on the recording day, SOUP told me, "Uh, we applied for the Towayami Festival, but we didn't get in," and...
え、調べなかったんだ、応募してたのかいつって
"Uh, you didn't check? You applied?" they said,
ちょっとプチ笑いというか。ということで、えー今日はね、さっきも言った通り、新衣装、3Dの新衣装もありますし、他にもなんと発表がありますので、ぜひ最後までここに座り続けてください。
just a little chuckle. So today, as I said earlier, we have a new 3D costume, and also announcements, so please keep sitting here until the very end.
はい、で、そしてハッシュタグのお知らせです。ぴっ、こちら。はい、ハッシュタグトワヤミ生誕祭2026になりますので、ぜひたくさん感想をポストしてくださいね！美人の写真のスクショも待っておりますよ！
Yes, and next is an announcement about hashtags. Right here. The hashtag is #TowayamiSeitansai2026, so please post lots of impressions! I'm also waiting for screenshots of your beautiful photos!
はい。はい。で、えっと曲の振り返りなんですが、一曲目が先駆けを、ファーストソロライブの衣装を着て歌わしていただきました。
Yes. Yes. And looking back at the songs, the first song was "Sakigake", which I sang wearing my 1st solo live costume.
そして2曲目はですね、深海をセカンドソロライブの衣装で歌わしていただきました！イエーイ！
And the 2nd song was "Shinkai", which I sang in my 2nd solo live costume! Yay!
あの、そこまで意図してなかったんだけど、どちらの曲もね、ソロライブの、1番最本当の最後のアンコールの最後の曲だったんですよ。どっちも好きだから入れただけなんですけど。
I didn't intend it that way, but both songs were actually the very last encore song of the solo live. I just put them in because I like both.
はい、なんかこの収録をしてる時に、どっちのソロライブの景色が思い出して、ちょっとエモかったです！はい、是非Blu-rayも発売するのでゲットしてくださいね！
While recording this, remembering the scenery of both solo live shows made me a bit emotional! Yes, Blu-ray is also going on sale so please get it!
はい、そして次なんですけれども、えーなんと先日ソロライブを終えた、あの超超超超超大物ゲストと一緒に歌っちゃいます！
Yes, and next, amazingly, I'll be singing together with the super-duper-mega-huge guest who just finished her solo live the other day!
えー、もう言っちゃうと、ねねちが！ねねち、ねねねが来てくれます！
If I just say it, Nenechi! Nenechi, Nenene is coming!
ねねねとね、えー先日6月28日になんと、これなんかもう受け入れてる形にはなってるんだけど、ねねねトワはカップル4周年記念！
Nenene and, the other day on June 28th, amazingly, well, it's accepted like this, Nenene and Towa are 4th anniversary couple!
ねねねカップル、ねねトワは4周年記念になりまして、そこで初めており曲を出したんですよ。その曲を今日はダンスフルバージョンでお届けしたいと思います！うちしか勝たん、どうぞ！
NeneTowa is celebrating their 4th anniversary, and for that we released our first original song. We'll deliver that song today in a dance-full version! #UchiraShikaKatan, go!
漏れてる角度で切り取る今日だって
Even today, captured from a leaking angle,
それだけじゃ満たされないでしょ？
that alone isn't enough to satisfy you, right?
Got it, Move... Wow
Don't Say No JUST LIVE MORE
サバイバル You got to move
It's survival, you got to move.
現代はさながら戦国
The modern age is like a warring state.
誰が勝ち抜ける?
Who can come out on top?
鍵は開けられてしまった
The locks have already been opened.
(Don't Say No JUST LIVE MORE...)
どこにある? どう使う?
Where is it? How do we use it?
禁断の果実
The forbidden fruit?
「今」という 風は 何を伝えるため
What is the wind called 'now' trying to tell us?
[おまえのもとに吹く? 強く強くBlowin' up]
[Blowing strongly right to you? Blowin' up!]
明日が 夢が まだ見えなくても
Even if tomorrow and our dreams are still out of sight,
[そこ限界? 精一杯 生きてると言えるなら]
[At your limit? If you can live to the fullest]
うつむくなよ(顔を上げろ)
Don't hang your head (Keep your head high)
どこまででも(曲げることなく)
No matter how far (Without ever backing down)
信じた道を行け JUST LIVE MORE
Follow the path you believe in, just live more!
Don't Say No JUST LIVE MORE
花道フィロソフィー
Hanamichi philosophy,
勝たなくちゃすぐに崖っぷち
If you don't win, you're at the edge of a cliff.
戦いはNever end
The battle is never-ending,
最後の1人になるまで
Until you're the last one standing.
(Don't Say No JUST LIVE MORE...)
見ぬフリか もぎ取るか
Will you pretend not to see, or snatch away
禁断の果実
The forbidden fruit?
「今」という 空は 何を見せるために
What is the sky called 'now' trying to show?
[真っ赤に燃えている? 熱く熱くBurnin' sun]
[Burning deep red? Hotter and hotter, burnin' sun]
強さで何を 証明するのか
What are you trying to prove through your strength?
[お前だけに 聞いてるんだ 壊すのか守るのか]
[I'm asking you: will you destroy or protect?]
足跡さえ(誰もいない)
Even if you leave no footprints (With no one around)
見えなくても(世界の果て)
Even if you can't see (At the end of the world)
信じた道を行け JUST LIVE MORE!
Follow the path you believe in, just live more!
この争いを 終わりに出来る誰かは
Who can put an end to this conflict?
天下無双の勝者
The peerless victor.
止まんない ビビんな
Don't stop, don't be scared,
想ったそのままでYou're on the right track
Just as you thought, you're on the right track.
JUST LIVE, JUST LIVE, JUST LIVE MORE
閉じ込めるライトで塗り替える今日
Painting over today with trapping lights,
でも綺麗なだけじゃ Oh no no
But just being pretty is oh no no.
つまらないでしょ
That's so boring, right?
想像以上のShow
A show beyond your imagination,
期待以上を見せてほしいの
I want you to show me beyond expectations.
ねえ もっと近づきたいでしょ
Hey, you want to get closer, right?
本音まで知りたいでしょ
You want to know my true feelings, right?
ねえ もっと目を逸らさないでしょ
Hey, you won't look away anymore, right?
あたししかいないでしょ
There's only me for you, right?
ねえ もっと
Hey, more...
目も合わさないでしょ
...you won't even meet my eyes?
あたししかいないでしょ
There's only me for you, right?
完全優勝でしょ
An absolute victory, right?
まだまだ足りない
It's still not enough,
新しい時代へのLike
Like toward a new era.
絶対運命でしょ
It's absolute destiny, right?
いや まだ足りない 愛足りない
No, it's still not enough, love is not enough.
サヨナラは言わないでしょ
You won't say goodbye, right?
あたししかいないでしょ
There's only me for you, right?
カタン カタン カタン
Clack, clack, clack,
あたししか カタン カタン
Only me, clack, clack.
完全優勝でしょ
An absolute victory, right?
まだまだ足りない
It's still not enough,
新しい時代へのLike
Like toward a new era.
絶対運命でしょ
It's absolute destiny, right?
いや まだ足りない 愛足りない
No, it's still not enough, love is not enough.
カタン カタン カタン あたししか
Clack, clack, clack, only me.
カタン カタン カタン うちらしか
Clack, clack, clack, only us.
カタン カタン カタン あたししか
Clack, clack, clack, only me.
カタン カタン カタン うちらしか
Clack, clack, clack, only us.
カタン カタン カタン あたししか
Clack, clack, clack, only me.
カタン カタン カタン うちらしか
Clack, clack, clack, only us.
はーい！ということで、
Hi there! So,
えー、ねねねとわはね、うちらしか勝たん！でしたー！
Nenene and Towa's performance was 'Only us girls win!'!
どうだったでしょうか？ダンス、頑張りました！
How was it? We worked really hard on the dance!
ねねねありがとうー！
Nenene, thank you!
はい、ちょっとギャルっぽい感じで、振り付けもね、えー、あいり先生につくってもらいました！
Yeah, with a gyaru vibe, Airi-sensei choreographed it for us!
もとはね、「ガタン カタン」が結構好きで、このピースのとこ、「ガタン カタン ガタン」これがね、ギャルっぽくて可愛くて、すごく好きです。
I really liked the 'clack clack' part, and this peace sign part, so cute.
ぜひ踊ってみてね、(笑) 踊ってみてね、むずいな。
Definitely try dancing to it... haha, try dancing to it, it's pretty hard though.
はい、ぜひね、あの、いっぱい繰り返し、見てもらえればなと思います！
Yeah, I hope you'll watch it over and over again!
聞いてね、曲も。
And listen to the song too.
はい！ということで、お待たせいたしました！
Alright! So, thank you for waiting!
このあとは、とことわちゃん、新、新、3D、いや違う、3D新衣装の発表と いうことで、
From here on, Tokotowa-chan's new... wait, the 3D new outfit announcement,
着替えて来たいと思います！着替えます。
I'll go get changed! I'm going to change.
あ、じゃあ、着替えますからね、着替えますからね。
Ah, well, I'm going to change now, so.
うんしょ、うんしょと。 はあー、大変だ。すごいやっぱり、う、うわっ！
Heave-ho, heave-ho. Phew, this is tough. Wow, as expected, ugh—!
どんなんだよ！
What is this?!
ということで、着替えてきました。では、いいですか？
And so, I've changed. Well then, are you ready?
行きますよ、皆さん！
Here we go, everyone!
行きますよ！
Here we go!
なんか、ザボンさん、ドドリアさん来た。は、あ、や、はい、あ、美しい足が。
Zabon-san, Dodoria-san are here. Ah, yeah, yes, ah, beautiful legs.
美しい足が出ております。
My beautiful legs are on display.
バランスが取りづらい。
It's hard to keep my balance.
どう？ほら、まず、この足。
How are they? Look, first of all, these legs.
なんか最近のさ、流行りなよ、この薄々の靴下、これ名前なんて言うのかわかんないけど。
You know, lately it's trendy, these sheer socks... I don't know what they're called though.
え、シューズはね、最近、HIRO先生に書いていただいたんですけども、先生のね、あの、
Um, the shoes were designed recently by Hiro-sensei, and the sensei's... um,
ちょっとスカートの
Let's see, the skirt—
あっ、やばいスカートって言っちゃった。あっスカートじゃない、
Ah, oops, I said skirt! Ah, not skirt,
の、とこまで。
up to this part!
よし、スタート！
Okay, start!
はい！スカート、こんな感じになってます。
Right! The skirt is like this.
スカートというか、これ、なんていうか？
Or rather than a skirt, what should I call this?
一応、ズボンなんですよね。
It's technically pants, you see.
はい、で、見て！
Right, and look!
可愛くない？
Isn't it cute?
ぴ、ぴびの、キーホルダーだ。もにょもにょもにょもにょ
Pi-bibi's keychain! Squish squish squish...
可愛い。
Cute!
もにょもにょもにょもにょ
Squish squish squish...
はい、キーホルダーがついてたりとか、
Right, there are keychains attached,
ちゃんと、しっぽがでるようになってたりとか、
and it's designed so her tail can poke out properly,
しております。
and all that.
そして見てください、
And please look,
ネイルと指輪 アクセサリー。
nails, rings, and accessories!
ほら、こんな感じです。
See, it looks like this.
びん！ってギャルで可愛いでしょう？
Ta-da! Very gyaru and cute, right?
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい、で、これで多分みんなスクリーンショットしたから、
Right, and since everyone probably took screenshots of this,
え、ネイル、え、案外トワのネイル真似する人いっぱいいるんですよ、だから。
um, nails— there are actually a lot of people who copy Towa's nails, so...
このネイルを、多分真似してくれるでしょう。
you guys will probably copy this nail design, right?
はい、ということで、ちょっと見えてきちゃってますけれども、ちょっと首のとこまで。
Right, so, it's already coming into view, but up to the neck area.
じゃ、あげて、あげて。っだ！うわ！
Let's lift it up— Whoa!
やばい、髪の毛が、なんか長くなくない？ちょっと髪の毛長くない？
Whoa, isn't my hair kind of long? Isn't my hair a bit long?
なんかちょっとおばさんみたいな言い方になってる。
That sounded like something an old lady would say.
はい、で、これがジャケットですね。
Right, and this is the jacket!
ジャケットに、ちょっとスケ感があるトップスにということで、
A jacket with a somewhat sheer top underneath, so...
はい、腕にはトワと、トコ闇トワと書いてあります。
right, on the arm, it says "TOWA" and "Tokoyami Towa".
こっちは何にもない。
This side has nothing on it.
はい、ちょっと後ろ見ちゃうと、なんかストレートじゃない？髪の毛が。ということで、上までいっちゃいますか。
Right, if we look at the back— whoa, isn't it straight? The hair. So, should we go all the way up?
はい、どーん！
Here we go, ta-da!
じゃーーん！ということで、帽子も被ったりして、こんな感じです！いえーい！
Ta-da! So, I'm wearing a cap too, and it looks like this! Yay!
はい、どうでしょう？はい、今撮るとこですよー。はい、撮るとこですよー。イエーイ！はい。
How is it? Right, now's the photo spot! Right, photo spot! Yay! Yes.
そう、今回キャップ、キャップなんです。ちょっとストリート系というか、何ていうか。
That's right, this time it's a cap, a cap! A bit of a street style, or whatever you call it.
でしょ？で、あとは、こっちだ。
Right? And then, over here.
ギャルっぽいキラキラ付いてます！
It's got gyaru-style sparkles attached!
これもセンスが高すぎてよく分かってないけど、付いてるやつ。
Even though the sense of style is so high I don't really get it, it's attached!
最悪だよ、自分で付いてるのに、センスが凄すぎるんですよね。いつも、あの、デザインしてもらうとびっくりします。おしゃれすぎて。
It's terrible, I attached it myself yet the style sense is just too incredible. Whenever they design things for me, I'm always amazed at how stylish it is.
で、あとちょっとかっこいいめのパールとチェーンのネックレス付けたりとかしております。
And also wearing a somewhat cool pearl and chain necklace, and all that.
裏はこんな感じ。
The back looks like this.
おっ、はい。では、
Oh, right. So,
なんと！この帽子、取れちゃうんです！ちょっと帽子取ってきますね。
believe it or not! This cap comes off! I'll go take off my cap real quick.
取れました！帽子。
I took it off! The cap.
すごいでしょう？もう、日差しを直撃続けしてしまいます。
Amazing, right? Now I'll be taking direct sunlight continuously!
っていうのは置いといて、はい、白いね、メッシュがついてたりとか、このキラキラっていうのがついてたりとか、あと
That aside, right, there's white mesh attached, and these sparkles attached, and also
今回はハーフ、ハーフアップというか、ハーフアップじゃないけど、ここ三つ編みで編み込みしてもらって後ろ、かわいく結んでます。こんな感じです。
this time it's a half-up— well, not quite half-up, but braided right here in front and tied up cute in the back. It looks like this.
これちゃんとイラストレーターさんのみんなが、ぱーーって描いてくれるのも楽しみにしてるので、ゆっくり見せてます。
I'm really looking forward to seeing how all the illustrators draw it, so I'm showing it slowly.
あとはもういつも通りピアスがバチバチ付いたりしてまーす。
And as always, I've got loads of piercings attached.
はい！で、今ちょっとまだジャケット着てるんですけれども、このジャケットを脱ぐと、あ、脱ぐことができるでしょ？脱ぐとどうなるか、見せたいと思います。
Right! And, I'm still wearing the jacket right now, but if I take off this jacket— oh, I can take it off, right? I want to show you what happens when I take it off!
この名残惜し出るのにハマってるかもしれない。ずわあああああ！えー
Maybe I'm just getting hooked on dragging out the anticipation. Yeaaargh! Um...
この叫び声、あっ、こんな感じです。
This screaming voice— oh, it looks like this.
え、20キロあるジャケットを脱ぎました！あ、帽子は30キロありました。
Um, I took off the 20-kilogram jacket! Oh, the cap weighed 30 kilograms.
すごい、今首が軽いです。
Amazing, my neck feels so light right now.
ということで、こんな感じ！
So, like this!
この、トワがわいわい言ってる間ね、スタジオはすっごいシーンとしてるからすっごい恥ずかしいんだよ。
While Towa is making all this noise over here, the studio is dead silent, so it's super embarrassing, you know!
はい、見てください。腕のアクセサリーがこんな感じで、しかも、タトゥーがここに！入っちゃってます！
Right, please look. The arm accessories look like this, and what's more, a tattoo is right here! It's on there!
そしてこっち。こっちもかっこいいアクセサリーを腕につけております。はい、で、こんな感じです。
And on this side. On this side too, I've got cool accessories attached to my arm. Right, and it looks like this.
はい、これでまた写真撮ってくださいね。いえい、はー
Right, please take pictures of this too. Yay, hah—
いぇい あ
Yay, ah—
分かった これや まずはい
I got it. This one, first, yes.
これね 写真撮ってねみんな
Take a picture of this, everyone—
はい ぴ あ、Cじゃない これ言っちゃだめだこと あ、ぴ はい
Yes. Pi— ah, not C, I shouldn't say that. Ah, pi, yes!
こんな感じです いぇーい
This is what it looks like. Yay!
後ろも はい こんな感じ すっきりするよね ジャケットないだけで
And the back. Yes, like this. It feels refreshing without the jacket.
で まださらにあるんです 実は この上 黒のトップス 色変わるんです 虹色に
And there's even more. Actually, the top here changes color. To rainbow colors.
ちょっと待っててください
Please wait a second.
えーっと 塗り替えてっと でも もう終わったから
Um, repainting it... But wait, I'm already done.
で でてきた はい じゃじゃーん 虹色ではないです 白です
And here it comes. Tada! It's not rainbow. It's white.
だから上と下 白白にすることができるんですよね
So you can make both the top and bottom white.
はい どうでしょう で まだね 他にも 実は組み合わせがあるんで どの組み合わせがよかったのか あとで教えてください
Yes, how is it? And there are actually other combinations too, so let me know later which one was best.
はい で あ これスクショしてくださいね はい スクショタイム この時点で何をしたいのか分かった人 静かにですよ はい
Yes, and— ah, please take a screenshot of this. Yes, screenshot time! If you know what I'm trying to do, keep it quiet, okay? Yes!
でわ そしてなんと 下もね 実は変わるんですよ
Well then, and amazingly, the bottom actually changes too.
しゅるすぎる 玉で言うなら反対側帰れよみたいな感じだけど
Too fast! It's like 'go back to the other side!' though.
じゃーん 黒色 じゃーん こっちが白で こっちが黒 どうでしょう
Tada! Black! Tada, this side is white, and this side is black. How is it?
最初とは違う色になってますけれども ま 黒白ででもね かっこいい感じ シンプルだけど かっこいいみたいな感じで 色違いも作ってもらえました いぇーい
It's a different color from the beginning. But even in black and white, it's cool—simple yet cool, and she made a color-swapped version for me! Yay!
さっきこう こうできたから こう え こう ダサすぎる ま なんかいいようにしてください いぇーい
Earlier I did it like this, like this, so... like this? Eh, like this? So lame. Well, please make it look good. Yay!
じゃ そんな感じでね え とゆーことで 上が白黒 下も白黒ということでね 上が白 下でね え 白黒白黒でね 好きな組み合わせにできる え 一緒になっております ありがとうございます
So like that. Um, so top is black and white, bottom is black and white, so top white, bottom... um, black and white, black and white, you can choose your favorite combination, we made it together! Thank you!
はい ではじゃあ最初の服に戻ろうかな 少々お待ちください
Yes, well then, shall I go back to the first outfit? Please wait a moment.
ふう この30キロの帽子と20キロのジャケットを着て で 服も塗り替えてまたペンキべたべたで戻ってきて
Phew, wearing this 30-kilo hat and 20-kilo jacket, repainting the clothes and coming back covered in sticky paint...
はい ということで 最後 あちょっと待って 最後ね はい これ 最後こう こうか こうじゃない
Yes, so finally, ah wait, finally, yes, this. Finally, like this? Like this?
まあ いいようにしてください はい ということで いっぱい 各色違いにスクリーンショットゾーンを撮ったんですけど
Well, please make it look good. Yes. So, I took screenshot zones for each color variation.
どうでしたか TOWAという文字を作りました ぜひ ぜひ どうぞ 何を
How was it? I made the letters TOWA! Please, please, go ahead. What?
何をどうぞって感じなんだけど ま ということで こんな感じで新衣装はこういう風になっておりまーす いぇーい いっぱいね ふぁーととかね
What do you mean 'go ahead'? Well, so, like this, the new outfit is like this! Yay! Lots of, like, 'pha-' or something.
ね いっぱい書いてくれたら嬉しいです いつもありがとうございます ということで このあとは嬉しいお知らせとなります
You know, I'd be happy if you wrote a lot! Thank you always! So, after this comes happy news!
え 常闇トワ誕生日記念2026のグッズの発売決定 いぇーい
Tokoyami Towa Birthday Commemoration 2026 merchandise release confirmed! Yay!
こちらの配信後に発売開始となりますので 概要欄をチェックしてまわってくだされね ということで 気になるグッズの詳細は こちらをご覧ください どうぞ
Sales will start after this stream, so please check the description box! So, for details on the merchandise you're curious about, please take a look at this! Go ahead!
うわー うわー う いしょっと え ということでき イラストは miao先生に描き下ろしていただきました いぇーい
Whoa! Whoa! U-ishoht. Um, so, the illustrations were freshly drawn by miao-sensei! Yay!
かわいいでしょ これ え 旅行 お出かけをイメージして描いてもらいまして
Isn't it cute, this! Um, I had them draw it imagining a trip, going out,
今回の新衣装を えー モチーフとして モチーフというか 新衣装で描いてもらいました そしてね トワ様祭りや えー ランタン祭り 大好きなので そちらをモチーフにしてもらってます
and had them draw it using my new outfit as a motif—well, not motif, drawn in the new outfit! And also, I love the Towa-sama Festival and lantern festivals, so they made those motifs!
よし ということで こっから立ってね いしょっと はあ お待たせいたしました
Alright, so, standing up from here, u-ishoht. Phew, sorry to keep you waiting.
アイテムも紹介していきたいと
Items to introduce!
思います！まずは、こちら！
I'll start with the first one.
どうそ、ドン！
Here it is, boom!
願いを込めて、LEDアートパネル！
The LED art panel with wishes!
イェーイ！
Yay!
このね、あの先生に描き下ろしてもらったイラストを使って、アートパネルを作っちゃいました！
We made this LED art panel using an illustration drawn for us by Myao-sensei.
なんとこのアートパネル、LEDが入っておりますので、
And since this art panel has LEDs built into it,
ふんわり光っちゃいます！
it glows softly.
ちょっと美しい感じでしょ？
It's such a gorgeous look, isn't it?
ぜひこの際に手に入れてくださいね！
Please make sure to grab one!
はい！そして2つ目は、こちら！ボン！
Now, the second item is this, boom!
どっちのトワにする？リバーサルアクリルスタンド！
Which Towa will you choose? Reversible acrylic stand!
こちらはですね、この新衣装の取り下ろしとなっておりまして、
This is based on my new outfit, as you can see.
さっき色々帽子つけたりとか、上が黒だ下だ黒だ上白だ下が白だみたいな色々違いが見てたと思うんですけども、
Earlier we had all kinds of hat styles, like black on top, white on bottom, white on top, black on bottom, etc.
それをちゃんと表現してるアクリルスタンドになっております！
This acrylic stand properly captures all of those variations.
表のトワちゃん！裏のトワちゃん！どっちのトワだ！
The front-facing Towa or the back-facing Towa? Which Towa will you choose?
ということで、こちらもチェックしてみてくださいね！
So please make sure to check this out too!
はい！そして続いては、こちら！ボン！
Next up is this, boom!
新衣装モチーフキーホルダー！
New outfit motif keychain!
イェーイ！
Yay!
見てください。
Look at this.
これです、これ！
This is it!
このトワのビービーと、おらおら。トワと書いたこのキーホルダーが
This keychain featuring Towa and BB...
このキーホルダーが、ここのアクセサリーがキーホルダーになっちゃいます！
This keychain turns my actual accessories into a keychain!
イェーイ！
Yay!
このね、モチーフにしてますので、ぜひお揃いで手に入れて見てください。
It's made into a motif, so please get one to match and check it out.
パーツはそれぞれ取り外し可能になっております。
The parts can also be detached individually.
よろしくお願いいたします。
Thank you very much.
はい！そして最後は、こちら！ボン！
And finally, we have this, boom!
トワとお揃いキャップ！
Towa and matching cap!
イェーイ！
Yay!
このね、帽子とお揃いのキャップを発売することになりました！
We've released this hat that matches my own!
普段使いしやすいデザインにもなってますので、
It features a design that's easy to wear for everyday use.
ぜひ今日トワと一緒に帽子をつけたいなって方は購入してみてください！お願いします！
If you want to wear matching caps with Towa today, please purchase one! Thank you!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
あ、そうだ！戻る前に、
Oh, that's right! Before I go back...
この全部を買ったフルセット特典、あ、フルセット購入特典もあります！忘れておりました。
There are also special benefits for purchasing the full set that includes everything! I almost forgot.
フルセットをご購入いただいた皆さんには、
Everyone who purchases the full set...
複製サインと、あと今回はメッセージ入りポストカードをプレゼントしたいと思います！ぜひフルセットでご購入してみてください。
will receive a duplicated copy with a handwritten-style signature and a message postcard! Please make sure to get the full set.
はい、よろしくお願いしまーす！
Thank you so much!
で、ここから、あ、
And from here...
そうそう！ここもまだここに行って、なんとこれだけじゃないんですよ！
Oh that's right, there's still more here!
グッズだけじゃなくて、あ、グッズは概要欄もチェックしてほしいのと、
Not just the merch—make sure to check the description box for the merch info too!
あと、そうなんです！最初のね、配信の最初に言ったと思うんですけども、お知らせがまだ一個あるんですよ！
And, that's right, like I said at the start of the stream, there's still one more announcement!
はい！そのお知らせとは、こちら！ボン！
And that announcement is right here, boom!
新曲「SMASH IT UP！」が、この後24時から、レジになった瞬間からデジタルリリースされます！
My new song, "SMASH IT UP!", will be digitally released starting at midnight tonight!
イェーイ！
Yay!
いつもね、あのトワのね、楽曲とか作る時にすごくお世話になってる、磯野さんっていう方がいらっしゃるんですけど、磯野さんにね描き下ろしていただきました！
I always get so much help from Isono-san when making my songs, and I asked Isono-san to write this for me!
なんかその、結構ざっくり「トワっぽい曲でお願いします」と。
I asked for a song that felt vaguely "Towa-like."
「トワっぽい」と、結構お世話になってるんですよ。だから、トワの音域とか、どういうのが得意かっていうのをすごい知ってくださってるので、
"Towa-like" meaning he knows my vocal range and what suits me best.
じゃあその、なんか最大限に生かしたようなトワの曲を作ってくださいって言って、できた曲が「SMASH IT UP！」なんですよね。
So I asked him to make a Towa song that brings out those elements to the absolute max, and the song that came out of that is "SMASH IT UP!".
うん。
Mhm!
結構ね、なんか、でも来た時は、「トワ、歌えるかな」「トワっぽいかな」え、でもこういうイメージ抱いてるんだなっていうふうな感じで、すごく面白かったんです。なんだよね。でもね、その、不安だったんですよ、最初取るまでは。でも撮ってみたら、すごい自分になってて、かっこいい曲になったので、ぜひ
At first, I was worried whether I'd be able to sing it well or if it would sound "Towa-like," but once I tried singing it, it fit me so well and became such a cool song.
あの、購入して聴いていただければなと思います！ダウンロードして見てくださーい！
you should purchase and listen to it. Please make sure to download it!
はーい！
Yes!
じゃあね、じゃあどんな曲なんだよって、そんなんか、もうゼロでダウンロードなんてできないよって思うじゃないですか。
So, you might think, "What kind of song is it?" and "Surely you can't download a song with zero budget," right?
いやいや！今日はその、この発表した新曲で、本日のライブを締めくくりたいとこくっくく！
Well, actually, today we're going to wrap up today's live stream with this newly announced song!
えっと、ここカットして、ここカットしてって、カットしなくていいですからね！
Wait, cut that part out—no, you don't need to cut that out!
はい！ではそんな新曲で、本日のライブを締めくくりたいと、思います！
Right then, let's wrap up today's live stream with that new song!
いいですか？
Are you ready?
では本日最後の曲です。
Now, for the final song of today...
聞いてください！
Listen to me!
スマッシュイットアップ！
Smash it up!
常世の闇に囚われたまま
Trapped in eternal darkness,
奏でる悲鳴を
playing out screams...
聞かせて
Let me hear them.
さあ 爪を磨いたら
Come on, once you've sharpened your claws,
まだ子供のようなあなたのために
for someone like you, who's still a child—
ああ 試してみたいなら
Ah, if you want to test it out,
その愚かな手に手錠をかけて
go on and put handcuffs on those foolish hands.
常世の闇に囚われたまま
Trapped in eternal darkness,
甘い甘いガムを噛んでた
chewing on sweet, sweet gum,
いくつもの後悔を捧げて
offering up countless regrets.
さりげない合図に隠された
Hidden within a casual signal,
答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
I'll make you understand the answer right away.
微笑な嘘にまみれた
Smeared in smiling lies,
拒んだままに 受け止めてあげる
just as you refused, I'll accept you—
ほら悲鳴を聞かせて
come on, let me hear your scream.
さあ 指を鳴らしたら
Come on, once you snap your fingers,
この子猫のような私のために
for a kitten like me—
ああ 喉が渇いてた
Ah, my throat was thirsty,
薄紅の口に指を散らして
scattering my fingers across pale crimson lips.
狭い牢獄に閉じ込められたまま
Confined within a narrow prison,
首輪に繋がれたいのか?
do you want to be chained by the collar?
くだらないルールじゃ奪えない
You can't take it with petty rules—
自由はすでにこの手のなかにある
freedom is already in these hands.
愛情では計れない
It can't be measured by affection,
弱ったままに選ばせてあげる
I'll let you choose while remaining weak—
ほら心を開いて
come on, open your heart.
わからないふりをして 寝ぼけてるのか?
Are you playing dumb, still half asleep?
もっと熱い暗闇を見せて?ね?
Show me even hotter darkness, won't you?
さりげない合図に隠された
Hidden within a casual signal,
答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
I'll make you understand the answer right away.
微笑な嘘にまみれた
Smeared in smiling lies,
拒んだままに 受け止めてあげる
just as you refused, I'll accept you.
常世の闇に刻むこの名を
Engraving this name into the eternal darkness,
わからせてあげる
I'll make you understand.
ほら悲鳴を聞かせてよ
Come on, let me hear your screams!
夢見ないで
Don't dream,
ほら聞かせて
come on, let me hear it.
常世の闇に囚われたまま
Trapped in eternal darkness,
奏でる悲鳴を
playing out screams...
聞かせて
Let me hear them.
くだらないルールじゃ奪えない
You can't take it with petty rules—
自由はすでにこの手のなかにある
freedom is already in these hands.
愛情では計れない
It can't be measured by affection,
弱ったままに選ばせてあげる
I'll let you choose while remaining weak—
ほら心を開いて
come on, open your heart.
わからないふりをして 寝ぼけてるのか?
Are you playing dumb, still half asleep?
もっと熱い暗闇を見せて?ね?
Show me even hotter darkness, won't you?
さりげない合図に隠された
Hidden within a casual signal,
答えはすぐにわからせてあげる
I'll make you understand the answer right away.
微笑な嘘にまみれた
Smeared in smiling lies,
拒んだままに 受け止めてあげる
just as you refused, I'll accept you.
常世の闇に刻むこの名を わからせてあげる
Engraving this name into the eternal darkness, I'll make you understand.
ほら悲鳴を聞かせてよ
Come on, let me hear your screams!
夢見ないで
Don't dream,
ほら聞かせて
come on, let me hear it.